<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Work Journal</title>
  <link href="http://drxyang.github.ioindex.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="http://drxyang.github.io"/>
  <updated>Lisp error in nil: (wrong-type-argument integerp nil)</updated>
  <id>http://drxyang.github.ioindex.xml</id>
  <entry><title type="html">Organize my files</title><author><name>Xin Yang</name></author><link href="http://drxyang.github.io/blog/2014/08/09_organize-my-files.html"/><updated>2014-08-09T22:02:00Z</updated><published>2014-08-09T22:02:00Z</published><id>blog/2014/08/09_organize-my-files.html</id><category scheme="/tags/summary.html" term="summary" label="summary"/><category scheme="/tags/org.html" term="org" label="org"/><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
To keep my files organized, secure and low-cost, I use:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dropbox Free (5.2 GB): work files, most valuable files
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project source code
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work documents
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading notes
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organized research files
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emacs files
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GTD files
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My local blogs
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emacs work files
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Drive Free (15 GB): frequently used references, shared files
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User manuals
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research literatures
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New downloads
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classic literatures
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ebooks
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequently used references
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current learning
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geek software test projects and examples
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shared files with colleagues
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft One Drive (15 GB): Shared files with family and friends
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photos
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pictures
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ebooks
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;External Hard driver 1: USB-Work (1 TB)
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My personal library
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All my ebooks and related code
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Useful websites copy
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My selection of good books
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scanned books
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Useful videos
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organized work files
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backups of Dropbox and Google Drive
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backups of my historical files
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software I am using
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtual machine files
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My hobby learning and projects
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;External Hard driver 2: USB-Backup (1 TB)
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup of USB-Work
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title type="html">【转】What is the relation between FFT length and frequency resolution?</title><author><name>Xin Yang</name></author><link href="http://drxyang.github.io/blog/2014/06/17_what-is-the-relation-between-fft-length-and-frequency-resolution.html"/><updated>2014-06-17T11:20:00Z</updated><published>2014-06-17T11:20:00Z</published><id>blog/2014/06/17_what-is-the-relation-between-fft-length-and-frequency-resolution.html</id><category scheme="/tags/dsp.html" term="dsp" label="dsp"/><category scheme="/tags/zz.html" term="zz" label="zz"/><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
REF: &lt;a href="http://electronics.stackexchange.com/questions/12407/what-is-the-relation-between-fft-length-and-frequency-resolution"&gt;Post @ stackexchange&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-1" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-1"&gt;Question&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If I have sampled a signal using proper sampling methods (Nyquist,
filtering, etc) how do I relate the length of my FFT to the resulting
frequency resolution I can obtain?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Like if I have a 2,000 Hz and 1,999 Hz sine wave, how would I
determine the length of FFT needed to accurately tell the difference
between those two waves?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-2"&gt;Answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The frequency resolution is dependent on the relationship between the
FFT length and the sampling rate of the input signal.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If the sampling rate of the signal is 10khz and we collect 8192
samples for the FFT then we will have:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
8192 / 2 = 4096 FFT bins
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Since, via nyquist, our signal contains content up to 5khz our bin
resolution is:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
5000Hz / 4096 bins = 1.22 Hz/bin
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This is may be the easier way to explain it conceptually but
simplified, your bin resolution is just:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="example"&gt;
FS/N
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
where FS is the input signal's sampling rate and N is the number of
FFT points used.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We can see from the above that to get smaller FFT bins we can either
run a longer FFT or decrease our sampling rate.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-1" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-2-1"&gt;The Catch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-2-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There is always a trade off between temporal resolution and frequency
resolution.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In the example above, we need to collect 8192 samples before we can
run the FFT, which when sampling at 10khz takes 0.82 seconds.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If we tried to get smaller FFT bins by running a longer FFT it would
take even longer to collect the needed samples.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That may be OK, it may not be. The important point is that at a fixed
sampling rate, increasing frequency resolution decreases temporal
resolution. That is the more accurate your measurement in the
frequency domain, the less accurate you can be in the time domain. You
effectively lose all time information inside the FFT length.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In this example, if a 1999Hz tone starts and stops in the first half
of the 8192 sample FFT and a 2002Hz tone plays in the second half of
the window, we would see both, but they would appear to have occurred
at the same time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You also have to consider processing time. A 8192 point FFT takes some
decent processing power. A way to reduce this need is to reduce the
sampling rate, which is the second way to increase frequency
resolution.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In your example, if you drop your sampling rate to something like 4096
Hz, then you only need a 4096 point FFT to achieve 1hz bins and can
still resolve a 2khz signal. This reduces the FFT bin size but also
reduces the bandwidth of the signal.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Ultimately with an FFT there will always be a trade off between
frequency resolution and time resolution. You have to perform a bit of
a balancing act to reach all goals.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title type="html">Wikipedian definitions of some scientific terms in hearing research</title><author><name>Xin Yang</name></author><link href="http://drxyang.github.io/blog/2014/05/05_wikipedian-definitions-of-some-scientific-terms-in-hearing-research.html"/><updated>2014-05-05T16:54:00Z</updated><published>2014-05-05T16:54:00Z</published><id>blog/2014/05/05_wikipedian-definitions-of-some-scientific-terms-in-hearing-research.html</id><category scheme="/tags/auditory.html" term="auditory" label="auditory"/><content type="html">

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-1" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-1"&gt;Physics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Physics (from Ancient Greek "knowledge of nature") is the natural
science that involves the study of matter and its motion through space
and time, along with related concepts such as energy and force. More
broadly, it is the general analysis of nature, conducted in order to
understand how the universe behaves.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-2"&gt;Biology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Biology is a natural science concerned with the study of life and
living organisms, including their structure, function, growth,
evolution, distribution, and taxonomy. Modern biology is a vast and
eclectic field, composed of many branches and subdisciplines. However,
despite the broad scope of biology, there are certain general and
unifying concepts within it that govern all study and research,
consolidating it into single, coherent fields. In general, biology
recognizes the cell as the basic unit of life, genes as the basic unit
of heredity, and evolution as the engine that propels the synthesis
and creation of new species. It is also understood today that all
organisms survive by consuming and transforming energy and by
regulating their internal environment to maintain a stable and vital
condition.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-3" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-3"&gt;Physiology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Physiology (from Ancient Greek 'physis', meaning "nature, origin", and
'-logia', meaning "study of" is the scientific study of function in
living systems. A sub-discipline of biology, its focus is in how
organisms, organ systems, organs, cells, and bio-molecules carry out
the chemical or physical functions that exist in a living system.
Giving the size of the field it is divided into among others: human
physiology, animal physiology, plant physiology, cellular physiology,
microbial physiology (see microbial metabolism), bacterial physiology,
viral physiology.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-4" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-4"&gt;Psychology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-4"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Psychology is an academic and applied discipline that involves the
scientific study of mental functions and behaviors. Psychology has the
immediate goal of understanding individuals and groups by both
establishing general principles and researching specific cases, and by
many accounts it ultimately aims to benefit society. In this field, a
professional practitioner or researcher is called a psychologist and
can be classified as a social, behavioral, or cognitive scientist.
Psychologists attempt to understand the role of mental functions in
individual and social behavior, while also exploring the physiological
and biological processes that underlie cognitive functions and
behaviors.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Psychologists explore concepts such as perception, cognition,
attention, emotion, phenomenology, motivation, brain functioning,
personality, behavior, and interpersonal relationships, including
psychological resilience, family resilience, and other areas.
Psychologists of diverse orientations also consider the unconscious
mind. Psychologists employ empirical methods to infer causal and
correlational relationships between psychosocial variables. In
addition, or in opposition, to employing empirical and deductive
methods, some—especially clinical and counseling psychologists—at
times rely upon symbolic interpretation and other inductive
techniques. Psychology has been described as a "hub science", with
psychological findings linking to research and perspectives from the
social sciences, natural sciences, medicine, and the humanities, such
as philosophy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-5" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-5"&gt;Sensation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-5"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In psychology, sensation and perception are stages of processing of
the senses in human and animal systems, such as vision, auditory,
vestibular, and pain senses. Included in this topic is the study of
illusions such as motion aftereffect, color constancy, auditory
illusions, and depth perception.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sensation is the function of the low-level biochemical and
neurological events that begin with the impinging of a stimulus upon
the receptor cells of a sensory organ. It is the detection of the
elementary properties of a stimulus.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-6" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-6"&gt;Perception&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-6"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Perception (from the Latin perceptio, percipio) is the organization,
identification, and interpretation of sensory information in order to
represent and understand the environment. All perception involves
signals in the nervous system, which in turn result from physical or
chemical stimulation of the sense organs. For example, vision involves
light striking the retina of the eye, smell is mediated by odor
molecules, and hearing involves pressure waves. Perception is not the
passive receipt of these signals, but is shaped by learning, memory,
expectation, and attention. Perception involves these "top-down"
effects as well as the "bottom-up" process of processing sensory
input. The "bottom-up" processing transforms low-level information to
higher-level information (e.g., extracts shapes for object
recognition). The "top-down" processing refers to a person's concept
and expectations (knowledge), and selective mechanisms (attention)
that influence perception. Perception depends on complex functions of
the nervous system, but subjectively seems mostly effortless because
this processing happens outside conscious awareness.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-7" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-7"&gt;Cognition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-7"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cognition is the process by which the sensory input is transformed,
reduced, elaborated, stored, recovered, and used. In science,
cognition is the mental processing that includes the attention of
working memory, comprehending and producing language, calculating,
reasoning, problem solving, and decision making. Various disciplines,
such as psychology, philosophy and linguistics all study cognition.
However, the term's usage varies across disciplines; for example, in
psychology and cognitive science, "cognition" usually refers to an
information processing view of an individual's psychological
functions. It is also used in a branch of social psychology called
social cognition to explain attitudes, attribution, and groups
dynamics. In cognitive psychology and cognitive engineering, cognition
is typically assumed to be information processing in a participant's
or operator's mind or brain.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Cognition is a faculty for the processing of information, applying
knowledge, and changing preferences. Cognition, or cognitive
processes, can be natural or artificial, conscious or unconscious.
These processes are analyzed from different perspectives within
different contexts, notably in the fields of linguistics, anesthesia,
neuroscience, psychiatry, psychology, philosophy, anthropology,
systemics, and computer science. Within psychology or philosophy, the
concept of cognition is closely related to abstract concepts such as
mind, intelligence. It encompasses the mental functions, mental
processes (thoughts), and states of intelligent entities (humans,
collaborative groups, human organizations, highly autonomous machines,
and artificial intelligences).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-8" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-8"&gt;Psychophysics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-8"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Psychophysics quantitatively investigates the relationship between
physical stimuli and the sensations and perceptions they affect.
Psychophysics has been described as "the scientific study of the
relation between stimulus and sensation" or, more completely, as
"the analysis of perceptual processes by studying the effect on a
subject's experience or behaviour of systematically varying the
properties of a stimulus along one or more physical dimensions".
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Psychophysics also refers to a general class of methods that can be
applied to study a perceptual system. Modern applications rely heavily
on threshold measurement, ideal observer analysis, and signal
detection theory.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Psychophysics has widespread and important practical applications. As
just one example, in the study of digital signal processing,
psychophysics has informed the development of models and methods of
lossy compression. These models explain why humans perceive very
little loss of signal quality when audio and video signals are
formatted using lossy compression.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-9" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-9"&gt;Pschoacoustics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-9"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Psychoacoustics is the scientific study of sound perception. More
specifically, it is the branch of science studying the psychological
and physiological responses associated with sound (including speech
and music). It can be further categorized as a branch of
psychophysics.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-10" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-10"&gt;Psychology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-10"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Psychophysics quantitatively investigates the relationship between
physical stimuli and the sensations and perceptions they affect.
Psychophysics has been described as "the scientific study of the
relation between stimulus and sensation" or, more completely, as "the
analysis of perceptual processes by studying the effect on a subject's
experience or behaviour of systematically varying the properties of a
stimulus along one or more physical dimensions".
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Psychophysics also refers to a general class of methods that can be
applied to study a perceptual system. Modern applications rely heavily
on threshold measurement, ideal observer analysis, and signal
detection theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-11" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-11"&gt;Psychophysics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-11"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Psychophysics quantitatively investigates the relationship between
physical stimuli and the sensations and perceptions they affect.
Psychophysics has been described as "the scientific study of the
relation between stimulus and sensation" or, more completely, as "the
analysis of perceptual processes by studying the effect on a subject's
experience or behaviour of systematically varying the properties of a
stimulus along one or more physical dimensions".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-12" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-12"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-12"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The main differences:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objective
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subjective
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title type="html">Software I used for research</title><author><name>Xin Yang</name></author><link href="http://drxyang.github.io/blog/2014/03/20_software-i-used-for-research.html"/><updated>2014-03-20T23:45:00Z</updated><published>2014-03-20T23:45:00Z</published><id>blog/2014/03/20_software-i-used-for-research.html</id><category scheme="/tags/summary.html" term="summary" label="summary"/><category scheme="/tags/software.html" term="software" label="software"/><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
I am using lots of software for my research. It is a good idea to
summarize them before my computer crashes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-1" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-1"&gt;Web services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-1-1" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-1-1"&gt;File storage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-1-1"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dropbox: my work files
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Drive: ebooks, research literatures
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft One Drive: family shared files
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sina 微盘: downloaded ebooks from 爱问知识人 
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-1-2" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-1-2"&gt;Email&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-1-2"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gmail
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hotmail
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QQ mail
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-1-3" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-1-3"&gt;Notes taking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-1-3"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evernote: PC上主要用来抓取保存网页，平板上随手记些东西
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Keep: 不常用
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-2"&gt;Desktop software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-1" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-2-1"&gt;Email client&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-2-1"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thunderbird
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AttachmentExtractor
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Folderpane Tools
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MinimizeToTray revived
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-2" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-2-2"&gt;Web browser&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-2-2"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firefox: productive
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adblock Plus
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DownloadHelper
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evernote Web Clipper
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flash Block
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FlashGot
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Print Pages to PDF
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xmarks
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chrome: entertainment and Google services
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adblock Plus
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evernote Web Clipper
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unblock YouKu
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xmarks
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-3" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-2-3"&gt;Editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-2-3"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GNU Emacs
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-4" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-2-4"&gt;Snapshot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-2-4"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PicPick
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-5" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-2-5"&gt;Screen cast&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-2-5"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camtasia Studio
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-6" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-2-6"&gt;PDF tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-2-6"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDF reader 
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SumatraPDF: quick and refresh-able
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acrobat: official/standard PDF reader, for some advanced features
(JScript support) 
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDF editor
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foxit: fill PDF forms
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acrobat Pro
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft office suite
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-7" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-2-7"&gt;Image editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-2-7"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gimp: GUI
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imagemagick: CLI
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphviz
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-3" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-3"&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-3"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emacs
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Texlive
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jabref
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MATLAB
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual Studio
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TI CCS
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title type="html">Speech and noise</title><author><name>Xin Yang</name></author><link href="http://drxyang.github.io/blog/2014/03/17_speech-and-noise.html"/><updated>2014-03-17T20:35:00Z</updated><published>2014-03-17T20:35:00Z</published><id>blog/2014/03/17_speech-and-noise.html</id><category scheme="/tags/idea.html" term="idea" label="idea"/><category scheme="/tags/aim.html" term="AIM" label="AIM"/><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Is it reasonable to assume:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speech enhancement algorithms are based on the understanding of speech
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noise reduction algorithms are based on the understanding of noise
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
AIM belongs to the first category.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title type="html">Mathematics Terms Review</title><author><name>Xin Yang</name></author><link href="http://drxyang.github.io/blog/2014/02/19_mathematics-terms-review.html"/><updated>2014-02-19T22:27:00Z</updated><published>2014-02-19T22:27:00Z</published><id>blog/2014/02/19_mathematics-terms-review.html</id><content type="html">

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-1" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-1"&gt;Probability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Quartile&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Box plot&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;google:transformation of random variables&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pages.ucsd.edu/~ssaiegh/poli270.html"&gt;POLI 270: Mathematical and Statistical Foundations&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/teaching/0708/Probabilty/"&gt;Cambridge Probability 2007-08&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://math.arizona.edu/~jwatkins/math363s14.htm"&gt;Arizona Mathematics 363 Introduction to Statistical Methods Spring 2014&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2&amp;sigma; 95.4%
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3&amp;sigma; ??
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-2"&gt;Linear algebra&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Symmetric matrix&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Hermitian matrix&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Orthonormal basis&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Eigendecomposition of a matrix&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Diagonal matrix&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Partial derivative&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Norm (mathematics)&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Matrix determinant lemma&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Matrix calculus&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Schur decomposition&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Invertible matrix&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;wiki:Positive Definite Matrix&lt;/i&gt; 
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.math.hmc.edu/math40-04/"&gt;Introduction to Linear Algebra Math 40, Harvey Mudd College&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title type="html">科大讯飞信息科技有限公司</title><author><name>Xin Yang</name></author><link href="http://drxyang.github.io/blog/2014/01/21_.html"/><updated>2014-01-21T05:11:00Z</updated><published>2014-01-21T05:11:00Z</published><id>blog/2014/01/21_.html</id><category scheme="/tags/news.html" term="news" label="news"/><category scheme="/tags/china.html" term="china" label="china"/><category scheme="/tags/speech.html" term="speech" label="speech"/><category scheme="/tags/industry.html" term="industry" label="industry"/><content type="html">

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-1" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-1"&gt;链接&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.iflytek.com/"&gt;科大讯飞官网&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-2"&gt;相关新闻&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-1" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-2-1"&gt;&lt;a href="http://digitalpaper.stdaily.com/http_www.kjrb.com/kjrb/html/2014-01/17/content_243263.htm?div=-1"&gt;科大讯飞：掌握语音产业话语权&lt;/a&gt; 吴长锋《科技日报》2014-01-17&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-2-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="oblog-phd/iflytek_news1.pdf"&gt;PDF文件存档&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-1-1" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="sec-2-1-1"&gt;创新驱动发展&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-2-1-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
当下，语音技术应用在生活中早已是触手可及。走在路上，你会发现很多对着手机“自言自语”的人。从18位大学生蹒跚创业，到领军中文语音技术龙头企业，彻底打破国外巨头垄断格局，发展成为亚太地区最大的语音上市公司，掌握全球最先进智能语音的核心技术，科大讯飞用了14年。
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-1-2" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="sec-2-1-2"&gt;走一条弯曲的直线&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-2-1-2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
科大讯飞董事长刘庆峰用“走一条弯曲的直线”描述科大讯飞的创业历程。他说，所谓直线是指目标明确、战略清晰，弯曲则意味着实现梦想和目标的过程曲折。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
``2000年，我们开发出了语音平台产品，与华为、联想、英特尔等50多个开发商建立了合作伙伴关系，但2001年的销售额离目标相差很大。我们也在问自己，要不要坚持走这条路？''
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
让机器说话，用的是语音合成技术；让机器听懂人说话，用的是语音识别技术。语音技术市场领域一直是国内外科学界和产业界关注的焦点和竞争的热点，科大讯飞对语音技术的产业化前景始终充满信心。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
如何在激烈的语音技术市场竞争中抢得发展先机？如何扭转国内语音应用市场被国外巨头垄断的不利局面？如何克服大学生的自身不利因素实现技术与产业的突破？答案只有一个，那就是自主创新。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
科大讯飞通过核心源头技术整合，与国内在语音领域积累深厚而又最具优势互补的中国科学技术大学、清华大学、中国社科院语言研究所成立紧密型联合实验室。通过创新机制，使合作伙伴专注于其擅长的研究，科大讯飞统一实施产业化，从源头技术上聚拢了语音的产业资源。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
在此基础上，科大讯飞与国家普通话培训测试中心共建联合实验室，推动语音和语言技术在语言文字培训、测试、评估和推广中的应用，逐步使该联合实验室成为在国内外汉语语言文字信息化研究和应用推广方面具有广泛影响的重要基地。与此同时，科大讯飞先后与新疆大学、内蒙古大学、西藏大学、云南大学、兰州大学建立联合实验室，深入开展以维语、蒙古语、藏语等为主的多民族语音合成、语音识别、语音评测、语音翻译等核心技术研发。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
目前，科大讯飞已占有中文语音技术市场50%以上市场份额，在金融、电信、保险等主流市场达80%以上，可以同时为全行业2000多家企业提供语音核心技术，并面向移动互联网时代全球语音应用热潮率先推出了语音云平台，用户数已经突破3亿，开发应用申请超过2万个，已逐步形成了以科大讯飞为核心的语音产业链，成为业界公认的“语音产业国家队”，牢牢掌握了民族语音产业的话语权。
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-1-3" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="sec-2-1-3"&gt;应用驱动市场&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-2-1-3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
在全世界范围内，语音技术走过了漫长的蛰伏期。随着智能手机兴起，语音技术应用迎来了爆发性增长，真正进入到普通人的生活，开始了一个前所未有的快速发展阶段。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
``国内正在形成持续的语音产业价值链，市场应用正在大踏步前进。''刘庆峰认为，目前中国在中英文语音产业方面的技术能力，已完全和世界一流同步。在产品应用中，只有在电信级大规模应用上，与美国、日本相比还略有差距；在消费类产品和终端产品方面的进展，反而超过了美国、韩国和日本。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
成立之初，科大讯飞面临着如何最大限度地抢占市场的问题。讯飞长于技术，因此企业定位从创业之始就很明确：做专业的语音技术提供商，专注于提供最核心的语音技术，打造一个从核心技术到二次开发厂商，再到终端用户的产业链，使得二次开发厂商能和科大讯飞一起携手合作，利益共享。科大讯飞不仅自己研发语音技术产品，还凭借自身技术优势，为各行各业的开发商提供易用的语音开发平台，为行业用户提供更加智能的语音技术解决方案，目前已与联想、华为、东软、英特尔等合作，帮助他们在系统和产品中进行语音技术的二次开发和推广。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
在市场应用上，科大讯飞重点打造语音产业基地，为加速形成围绕讯飞语音核心技术的应用开发集群创造了条件，并积极探索创业业务模式，坚持``软件＋硬件''
``软件＋服务''的产品创新与商业模式创新，加速推动语音技术飞入千家万户。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
2011年，国家智能语音高新技术产业化基地、语音及语言信息处理国家工程实验室等国家级平台相继落户讯飞。为与之对应，科大讯飞加速了应用创新平台建设，相继成立了语音平台与嵌入式研发部、口语评测研发部、通信增值研发部、行业软件研发部等应用研发部门，真正实现了从基础研究、应用研究到市场应用的对接。联合实验室负责人、研发部负责人、产品市场经理就某项创新进行面对面的沟通，通过沟通交流，市场方向更加明确，技术研究更加专注。目前，科大讯飞每年推出新产品20项以上，新产品销售收入占总收入比重超过80%。
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-1-4" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="sec-2-1-4"&gt;创新铸就品牌&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-2-1-4"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
科大讯飞始终认为，``一流企业满足市场，超一流企业创造市场''。要想创造出竞争对手难以仿效的市场，就需要具备别人难以仿效的核心技术竞争优势，形成差异化的竞争亮点，打造出中国语音产业的第一品牌。而科大讯飞研发支撑体系建设，围绕语音技术从原始创新到技术成果商品化和产业化，形成完整的协作支撑和运作体系，构建语音产业从核心技术到市场应用的全方位领先，形成竞争对手难以模仿的优势。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
多年来，科大讯飞在``顶天立地''发展战略的指引下，努力打造``iflytek
inside''品牌战略。通过核心技术的国际领先和研究成果大规模的产业化，使科大讯飞品牌真正深入亿万家庭，真正实现``让世界聆听我们声音''的产业理想。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
科大讯飞的中文语音合成技术在近年来历次国家863评比中均名列第一；英文语音合成技术在2006—2012年连续7次蝉联国际英文合成大赛全球第一名，2008—2012年连续5年在国际说话人、语种识别评测大赛中名列前茅；普通话口语评测技术是业界唯一经国家语委评测可用于普通话等级考试的技术；嵌入式中文语音识别核心技术上也处于业界领先行列。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
通过多年积累，科大讯飞的语音技术现已广泛应用于电信、金融、社保、交通等各行各业的信息服务之中，并开始在手机、汽车导航、学习机、Mp3/Mp4、智能玩具等越来越多的数码终端产品以及汉语国际推广、国防等关键领域得到成功应用。
``未来，每一部手机、每一辆汽车、每一台家电、每一个玩具都将能听会说''，这正是讯飞追求的梦想。
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title type="html">中国助听器市场新闻几则</title><author><name>Xin Yang</name></author><link href="http://drxyang.github.io/blog/2014/01/20_.html"/><updated>2014-01-20T05:12:00Z</updated><published>2014-01-20T05:12:00Z</published><id>blog/2014/01/20_.html</id><category scheme="/tags/news.html" term="news" label="news"/><category scheme="/tags/china.html" term="china" label="china"/><category scheme="/tags/hearing-aid.html" term="hearing aid" label="hearing aid"/><category scheme="/tags/industry.html" term="industry" label="industry"/><content type="html">

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-1" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-1"&gt;链接&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chineseaudiology.com/"&gt;中国听力学网&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-2"&gt;相关新闻&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-1" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-2-1"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chineseaudiology.com/boke/html/20131785516.html"&gt;中国助听器发展回顾：阶段性和多元化&lt;/a&gt; 林学军《中国听力学网站》2013-10-22&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-2-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
中国已经成为全球助听器市场发展最快、潜力最大的一个特殊市场，并成为世界主要助听器跨国企业的重要发展基地。根据中国听力学网
www.chineseaudiology.com 的报道，瑞士助听器企业Sonova、德国西门子、丹麦的瑞声达等均将中国市场定义为未来增长的重镇，并加大投资，从生产到分销，从验配到培训，无不凸显各自的决心和实力，加快各自在这个市场份额的扩展。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
而在2013年来临之际，回顾中国助听器发展的历程也具有一定的启示意义。记者在采访中国听力学网和业内专家以及相关企业的基础上，撰写出这份回顾中国助听器发展简史，而阶段性和多元化发展正是这个时间不长的发展特征。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
虽然中国本土助听器的生产和销售早在20世纪50年代由天津助听器厂开始，但是由于技术和销售的不完善，一直到了上个世纪的80年代后期，随著国际助听器生产厂商进入中国才拉开了中国助听器发展的帷幕。最先进入中国的是丹麦达那福助听器公司（现丹麦大北集团瑞声达公司），他们率先到中国厦门设厂、生产助听器，并在国内开始建立销售渠道，一时称雄全国。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
进入90年代中期德国的西门子、瑞士的峰力集团、美国的斯达克公司、丹麦的奥迪康和唯听公司、加拿大的优力康、瑞士的伯纳锋等国外主要助听器厂商开始大举进入中国市场。相继在中国设立了工厂和销售中心。瑞士Sonova旗下的峰力集团、德国的西门子和美国斯达克公司在苏州建厂，开始生产包括出口的各式助听器和配件，丹麦的瑞声达仍然保留其在厦门的工厂。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
同时，中国国内助听器生产厂商也开始起步，当时主要在福州（丽声）、成都（微迪）和广东的小榄镇，后者目前依然是中国90％盒式机的生产基地。根据
2007年当时医疗器械出口统计，中国排在前十位的医疗器械出口产品中有三名是助听器生产公司，德国的西门子排在第三、丹麦的瑞声达排在第6、瑞士的峰力集团排在第九。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
到了90年代后期，一些二线助听器品牌相继进入中国，比如日本松下、索尼和理音（Rion）等日系企业，开始在中国建立代理销售，不过尚未在中国建立生产基地。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
伴随这些国际知名企业的到来，中国助听器行业开始进入了一个空前规模的快速发展。国内的部分企业开始转向生产助听器，如广东中山市、江苏盐城市、天津市、福建厦门市等地陆续建立了民营助听器工厂，主要生产低价位的盒式和中小功率耳背式助听器。如前所述，盒式机的主要生产基地是在广东的小榄镇，这些产品主要通过商业机构销售，数量较大，估计一年有近百万台的生产量。不过其品种、质量尚不能与国外独资企业生产的产品相提并论。从国内当时几次强制性助听器抽查结果来看，90％不合格的助听器主要来自国内的低端生产厂家。不过，目前大部分助听器的生产质量基本符合国家标准。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
当前，国际上最先进的助听器技术和产品在中国市场频频可见，从发布速度来看，国内外产品发布品种等均处在同一时间，在市场上，从耳背机到深耳道机、从单通道到多通道、从蓝也无线助听器到双耳互联助听器，具有各种专用功能的助听器在市场比比皆是，并基本得到消费者认可。同时，国内部分企业生产的助听器也开始获得一定的市场份额，比如位于厦门的欧仕达和新声、杭州的惠耳和成都的微迪数字等企业，不但开始和国际巨头争夺助听器市场，还快速在国际市场占据一席之地，为第三世界提供了大量的低价助听器。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
因此从助听器技术和先进程度上讲，中国市场的助听器基本和世界一致，并且新产品的发布也与发达国家同步。不过，中国市场助听器的验配、销售和使用因地域和经济发展不平衡、行业机制不健全、国家相关法规政策尚在制定等原因，处于发展阶段，全国各地水平参差不齐。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
回顾助听器在中国市场过去几十年的发展，可以用阶段性和多元化来总结其发挥咱的展特点以及趋势。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
第一阶段：上世纪80年代末90年代初，以柜台式销售为主。其特征是大部分助听器通过药店、百货商店里设立的药柜、医疗器械产品销售专柜进行销售。这个时期助听器无验配过程，患者通过临场试戴效果决定是否购买。无售后服务，无须专业测试等。 值得一提的是 1979年1月北京同仁医院、北京市耳鼻喉科研究所开设了国内首家助听器门诊，由邓元诚负责，并通过天津助听器厂为患者定制耳模。其后又定制耳内式助听器。由此开创了助听器国内专业选配的先河。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
第二阶段：到90年代中、后期，开始引进助听器验配，进入一个相对规范和科学化的阶段。除了医院开始增设验配中心外，开始出现以助听器专卖，以专业形式进行销售。部分大城市开设了专业化程度较高的助听器专卖店。这个阶段的特征是对患者听力进行检测，使用科学的方法对患者听力进行补偿，在此基础上验配助听器。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
在这个阶段，医院开始介入助听器的服务，如金济霖（阳中国医科大学第一附属医院）盛今蕙（上海第一医科大学眼耳鼻喉科医院）、黄燮康（上海建工医院）、许时辉（上海第一医院）、高成华（长春白求恩医科大学）、王尚礼（贵州医科大学）、简栋梁（广州聋校）、彭汉初（山西医科大学第一附属医院）、徐丽蓉
/闵家琳（四川华西医院）、梁涛（江苏徐州，中国听力医学基金会）、张华和张志勇（北京协和医院）、张建一和张正国（中国协和医大）、徐廷贵（南京海军
414医院）、王永华（浙江省中医学院）等全国各地耳鼻咽喉科出身为主的专家开始在医院（医学院）设立听力门诊，为患者专业选配助听器，并为听障者提供康复指导。而各地1200多所聋儿康复中心、800多所聋哑学校在各级残疾、民政部门、教育局等领导下，纷纷成立各种形式的选配中心，对聋儿进行测听、助听器选配。尤其是在聋儿康复方面做出了卓越的贡献。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
从零售的角度来看，此时销售模式主要通过助听器生产商赞助形式设立以产品为主的专卖店。发展最快的是德国和丹麦的厂家。此时专卖店的特点是买独家产品、规模偏小、助听器验配的主要设备多由生产厂家赞助，如听力计、助听器测试仪、耳模取样设备和材料等。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
第三阶段：21世纪初到目前，助听器零售进入了一个我们称为多品牌销售的阶段，虽然助听器生产商赞助的助听器店仍占市场一定份额，经营销售多家品牌助听器的销售店越来越多，这放映了市场的需求，也是随助听器各品牌营销宣传后，消费者逐渐了解了更多的助听器品牌，不局限对某单一品牌的选择，通过比较，最后做出决策。这个阶段的助听器店规模逐渐增大，并且开始以连锁店的形式出现在一些经济发达的大城市。部分助听器店的面积增加到60－150㎡左右，助听器验配的技术和手段也越加成熟。科学化的验配、理性的消费行为、有规模的市场营销、和医学专家的紧密配合、相关国家法规政策出台和逐步规范的市场监督、迅速发展的助听器行业的配套服务等大大促进助听器的推广和使用。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
目前中国有近3000家助听器专卖店和近1000家以医院为中心的助听器验配中心，这些专业验配机构已经成为中国推广助听器的主要渠道。而国家采购量也逐年增加，在刚刚颁布的国家“十二五”发展计划中，据悉期间仅助听器的投入将超过20
多亿元。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
对于未来发展趋势，中国听力学网汉东声总编认为至少有三个趋势；一是助听器零售渠道的整合式发展，区域性的大型连锁助听器企业将继续扩大其份额，并整合当地的市场，成为主要的供应商；二是政府采购和医疗保险埋单将影响中国助听器市场的价格、服务和竞争格局的新架构，目前残联作为最大的采购机构已经将助听器采购价格压到零售价的20%以下，形成巨大的价格反差；三是助听器研发技术在中国将成为一个重要的领域，将改变目前“研发在外，组装在内”的传统行业模式，和其他行业一样，中国在未来10年将成为助听器的研发、生产和销售重要市场。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
汉东声总编说“中国助听器市场目前仅仅是国际市场的一个‘餐后甜点’，各大公司
80%以上的销售来自欧洲和北美，中国市场贡献率不到10%。不过，如果看到几年前，中国市场销售才只有1%的话，其发展速度远比总量更为重要。中国听力学网看好中国助听器市场未来的发展以及对全球市场的影响。”
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-2" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sec-2-2"&gt;&lt;a href="http://health.sohu.com/20041117/n223025997.shtml"&gt;中国助听器市场95%为洋产品 主攻儿童市场&lt;/a&gt; 吴佶谊《信息时报》2004-11-17&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-2-2"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-2-1" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="sec-2-2-1"&gt;6大国际知名助听器厂家进入中国皆主攻儿童市场&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-2-2-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
几百近千元的国产助听器少人问津，上万元的洋助听器却非常畅销！国外产品占据了我国九成以上助听器市场，而且， 几万元的儿童高端产品一直风头不减。受高额利润支使，近年洋助听器产品纷纷抛弃庞大的老年人市场，面向儿童的产品占据大半江山。
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-2-2" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="sec-2-2-2"&gt;洋助听器主攻儿童市场&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-2-2-2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
“国外的助听器市场主要是针对老年人的，但中国市场截然不同，老人助听器卖不动，儿童助听器越贵越好卖。我们开始以老年产品为主，很难打开市场，后来转攻儿童市场，情况就好了很多。” 日前，维听助听器上海有限公司销售部经理高司备接受记者采访时如是说。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
记者在采访中了解到，中国的助听器市场近年表现出明显的“一边倒”趋势：本应成为市场主力的老年人用助听器一直“疲软”，且对价格异常敏感，稍有风吹草动销售马上急剧下降，尤其针对老年人的高价位助听器一直“蹒跚”前行，增长速度非常有限；而与之形成鲜明对照的是，中国市场对于儿童用助听器接受程度非常高，几万元的高端产品一直风头不减。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
受高额利润支使，洋助听器纷纷进入中国，记者在采访中了解到，目前洋助听器占据了95%以上的国内市场，而且纷纷抛弃老人市场，主攻儿童市场。
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2-2-3" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="sec-2-2-3"&gt;医院为唯一销售渠道&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-2-2-3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
据了解，助听器在国外在各大商超都可以买到，但是在中国除了西门在中国拥有门店外，其他“洋巨头”都毅然选择了把医院作为攻城略地的唯一渠道。据了解，目前国际上的6家知名助听器厂家已经全部进入中国。与其它领域激烈火拼不同的是，几大巨头在中国市场上一直相安无事。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
高司备告诉记者，维听从1998年进入中国以来，销售网络锁定在医院和各大城市。在广州，目前主要是通过中山医科大学、儿童医院、南方医院等医疗机构进行销售。“我们只有而且仅有一级代理商，也不会设立门店。我们的市场开拓就是依靠医院进行，而自己做的就是建立起与之相联接的售后专业服务中心。”
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
据了解，虽然维听没有设立任何门店，但是维听在中国市场一直保持30%以上的增长率，“我们要求我们的代理商至少从事助听器验配行业5年以上，而中国国内开设听力专业仅仅2年不到，外国巨头近来也就几年的时间，我们的这个要求实际上就把已经有成熟网络的人从源头上抓在手里了，这个市场很大。可以这么说，在中国助听器市场门店的作用、折扣的功效远远比不上人的深耕细作开拓出来的市场。”
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
借助医院单一的销售渠道是否能支持长久的发展？高司贝表示，以医院为主要渠道的好处是门诊量大，患者相信医生专业的推荐，但坏处也很明显，如医生的流动性比较大，一个医生的流动可能意味着这个市场立即就没有了。
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title type="html">读博5个月的体会</title><author><name>Xin Yang</name></author><link href="http://drxyang.github.io/blog/2014/01/19_5.html"/><updated>2014-01-19T21:19:00Z</updated><published>2014-01-19T21:19:00Z</published><id>blog/2014/01/19_5.html</id><category scheme="/tags/review.html" term="review" label="review"/><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
在过春节前总结一下自己的体会：
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-1" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-1"&gt;目标&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
在自己并不年轻时开始读博尤其需要明确目标。3年的时间对30多岁的人是非常大的成本，能收获到足够的人生资本非常重要。通过过去的5个月，我的目标更清晰了。
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;获得博士学位
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;为未来自己的事业提供一个更高的起点。
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;和小马哥一样，证明``我拿的回自己失去的''
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;弄清英国和欧洲学术圈的规则
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;学术界入门
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;选择好自己的研究方向
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在相关领域积累一定的知识和成果（多看书，多发点文章、专利等）
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;多接触认识该领域的专家，争取能进入他们的圈子（多参加会议）
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;联系国内的关系，为将来回国任教做做铺垫（多搜索国内高校的信息，联系一些人）
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;海外工作经验
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;体验一下欧洲工业界（读博期间各种在欧洲的workshop机会要好好珍惜，那些公司可能是我潜在的雇主）
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;接触欧洲行业内主要的公司，争取能去实习一下，为将来的工作职位谋出路。
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;了解国内行业内的情况，为今后回国发展铺铺路。
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;是否能拿到管理方向的硕士学位一个，为今后转型奠定基础
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;海外生活
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;适应海外生活方式
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;提升生活能力
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;提高英文能力
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-2"&gt;动力&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
在这么长的时间内，自我不断的精神激励非常重要。在目标明确的前提下，长时间动力的来源是
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;实现个人价值
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;履行家庭责任
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
亲人的情感支撑对我很重要。保持高昂的斗志和动力是解决做事情拖拉，难开始的唯一办法。
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-3" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-3"&gt;节奏&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
长时间以来自己很大的缺点
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;掌握不好生活工作的节奏
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;有计划无执行力，拖拉，时间浪费严重
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;并行处理事务能力差
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
这些其实都是``节奏感''不好的表现。如果需要让自己更进一步，优秀的节奏感非常重要。这就需要对自我有清醒准确的认知，并要有时间计划和自我控制的能力。
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-sec-4" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sec-4"&gt;对策&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-4"&gt;
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;心中时刻保持激励
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;时间用到刀刃上
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;做事要流畅：尽量在不犹豫不反复的状态下初步完成一件事，期间有问题的话先迅速记录，以后有条件再精细化（罗马不是一天建成）。
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;做可行的工作计划并一定完成计划
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;多写点心得体会心情感受等等。在茫然或是闲的时间来写，即使自我鞭策又是一种情绪释放减压。中英文都要写。
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title type="html">Tips for Reading Academic and Technical Literatures</title><author><name>Xin Yang</name></author><link href="http://drxyang.github.io/blog/2014/01/15_tips-for-reading-academic-and-technical-literatures.html"/><updated>2014-01-15T15:10:00Z</updated><published>2014-01-15T15:10:00Z</published><id>blog/2014/01/15_tips-for-reading-academic-and-technical-literatures.html</id><category scheme="/tags/read.html" term="read" label="read"/><category scheme="/tags/tips.html" term="tips" label="tips"/><content type="html">&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;不动笔墨不读书 （英文有一样的说法 always have a pen by your side?
Check!)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;使用纸笔记笔记比用电脑软件方便。（便携，画图，标识）
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;使用易于重新装订的笔记本（refile-able writing pad）
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;使用各种颜色的铅笔（可涂改）
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;打印要阅读的文章（可以高亮重点内容，可以在页面加入标注、笔记）
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;为文章每个段落标号以便于索引
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;一条笔记至少占一页
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;为每一条笔记标记时间日期和对应阅读文献的bibtex key以便于归档，记录每条笔记对应文章的段落标号
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;每条笔记有自己的标题和标记（title and tags）
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;阅读完毕后后使用扫描仪存档笔记和标注过的文章。
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;到达一定时间或阶段后复习（review）笔记，并按照一点逻辑组织他们（refile）。
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;组织完毕用扫描仪再次扫描存档。
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content></entry>
</feed>
